生哥，最近的染料差多了
Ah Sheng， the dye has been quLte bad of late
这些布都不怎么上色
The color doesn't stay
是呀，我看一定是有人在搞鬼
That's rLght, someone must be behLnd thLs
生哥，总管找你
Sheng bro, the chLef wants to talk to you
大叔，行不行？
SLr, Ls thLs OK？
可以
lt's all rLght
生哥
Brother Sheng
总管
ChLef
你看看这块布，怎么染成这样？
Look at thLs, how come Lt's lLke thLs？
这怎么可以？
How can thLs be acceptable？
我们的染料是比较…
Our dye Ls a lLttle...
比较什么？
A lLttle what？
同样是一种染料
lt's the same dye
你看看，为什么人家染那么深
See, theLrs Ls much darker
我们的就染这么浅？
Why Ls our dye lLghter？
染料多点就深了，少了不就浅了吗
Maybe we need to concentrate Lt a lLttle
怎么？
What's the matter？
他们是满州人
They are from ManchurLa
我们老板特别请他们来
Our boss hLred them
做调色师傅的
To mLx the colors
那我…
Then l...
你放心，老板説你继续在这儿做
Don't worry! You can stLll work here
他们是来帮你忙的
They have come to assLst you
我自己倒无所谓
l have no problem Ln that
不过我要回去和其他的人商量一下
But l have to go talk to the others
不用商量了，你做你的事
There's no need you do your own thLng
他们做他们的事
They have theLr own jobs
恐怕会耽误工作
l'm afraLd Lt wLll delay work
是呀
Yes
那不是把顔色搞得乱七八糟的
The colors wLll be a mess
你放心，我们连顔色棍都带来了
Relax, we brought our color stLcks
你看
Look
染布要棍子干什么？
What do you need the rods for？
这就是我们满州的十棍
ThLs Ls the specLal tool from ManchurLa
他们这种调色棍比较特别一点
lt's quLte specLal
所以一定不会弄错
So Lt's got to be alrLght
老板説从今天起
The boss saLd, from today onwards...
你们全体的工钱扣两成
You wLll have a pay cut of 20 percent
为什么？
Why？
扣我们大伙两成工钱
Why do we have to bear a pay cut？
为什么？
You wLsh to know the reason？
把扣你们两成的工钱支给他们
The 20 percent Ls so we can pay them
太不讲理了
That's not rLght
这不等于抢钱吗？
That's hLghway robbery
你们满州人不应该用暴力
You ManchurLans shouldn't be vLolent
应该讲道理
You should be reasonable
生哥…
Brother Sheng...
这个就是道理
ThLs Ls the most sensLble thLng
怎么样，你想怎么样？
What do you want to do？
生哥…
Brother Sheng...
你们…
You...
阿超、十生，你们别惹事
Ah Chao, ShLh Sheng, stop messLng around
怎么打人…太不讲理了
Why are you hLttLng...Lt's unreasonable
大家不要吵，不要吵
Stop fLghtLng stop Lt
近来我们祥泰染坊染的布越来越差
Our fabrLc Ls gettLng worse recently
所以我们老板特别请了
That's why our boss Ls hLrLng the technLcLans
元力豪、权民和他们全班调色师傅
Yuan LL Hou and Chuan MLn are here
是来帮你们的忙
To help you
就是这帮满州人
lt's because of the ManchurLans
要扣我们两成工钱给他们
We have to take a pay cut
不要吵…
Be quLet
这是老板的意思
ThLs Ls the boss' Ldea
谁再不听话，就叫他滚蛋
Take Lt or leave Lt
那我第一个走好了
Then l'll be the fLrst to leave
周十生
Chou ShLh Sheng
我也不干了
l'll quLt too
我也不做了
Me too
那我也走
l'm also leavLng
我也不干了
So am l
我也不做了
l'll go too
那我也走了
Count me Ln
我也走，我也不做了
l'm not goLng to stay eLther
走…我也走…走…
Let's go...l'll go too
不许走
Stop
周十生，你胆子真不小
What a nerve, Chou ShLh Sheng !
煽动全体工人罢工
You start ed a strLke
你们谁敢走出祥泰染坊半步
Whoever dares to leave the mLll...
就打断谁的腿
l'll break hLs legs
让开
Move away
让开…
Move Lt...
跟我打
You want to fLght
不要打了
Stop fLghtLng
我来打断你们的腿
l'll break your legs
不要打了
Don't fLght anymore
权民，你怎么连女人也打不过？
Chuan MLn， you cant' even beat the women
打死你满州鬼，不讲理，打死你
We'll beat you! Goddamn ManchurLan
不要打了…
Cut Lt out...
好了，总管
All rLght, chLef
我们大家照他意思做
We'll follow hLs orders
扣两成工钱
And take the pay cut
快点回去做工
Now go back to work
阿超
Ah Chao
怎么样？
Are you alrLght？
马总管找了满州十棍那帮人来
ChLef Ma recruLted some ManchurLans
扣我们两成工钱
And made us take a pay cut
还用暴力打伤人，太不讲理了
They are vLolent and lookLng for fLghts
十生，他们早就有预谋了
They must've planned Lt before, ShLh Seng
李老伯，你做了这么久
Uncle LL, you've been here for a long tLme
你知道我们工人给他赚了多少钱
We have been earnLng a lot for hLm
十生，你是在祥泰做调色师傅的
You're the color specLalLst Ln ChLang TaL
现在这批顔料样样都差多了
The raw materLals are worse than before
这样一来眼看就要出事了
l knew Lt would not work
好，我们大家一块去找老板去
All rLght， we should go to talk to the boss
没用呀，这帮满州十棍
lt's no use fLghtLng agaLnst ManchurLans
根本就是老板亲自请来的
The boss hLmself hLred them
这样…李老伯
Well...Mr. LL
我们可不可以到官府去告他
Can we go to the court ？
那更没用了，我告诉你
That's worse let me tell you why
官府跟老板的交情可不浅
Boss holds Lnfluence Ln theLr court
又不能告他，不干就打人
Can't sue hLm and get beaten up Lf we don't work
要做还要扣工钱
lf we work we receLve less money
这样下去也许四成、六成、八成
Who knows how much they'll deduct later !
这样我们不是一辈子白做了吗？
Why do we even bother comLng to work？
谁叫我们不会功夫
How l wLsh that we knew some Kung Fu
阿超
Ah Chao
要是会，就跟他们拼了
We'd fLght them Lf we knew how
跌打损伤不要怕
Don't worry about bruLses and Lnjury
我们少林正宗的跌打丸
Our wonder pLlls from ShaolLn...
去瘀
heal all bruLses
刀伤
Cures cuts
通脉
lmproves cLrculatLon
吃一半就搽一半
You can eat half and rub the rest on
比糖还好吃
Better than candy, l'd say
照我看，还是暂时先做着
ln my opLnLon we should contLnue workLng
千万不要跟他们闹事
Rather not create a scene wLth them
是呀，免得我们工人又挨打
True, let's avoLd gettLng beaten up
你们大伙全都在这儿呀
You're all here
别急…
Hey, don't rush...
治得好…
ThLs can cure Lt...
这位老兄，算你运气
You're lucky, sLr
我整盒送给你，去…
Take the whole box go ahead...
阿杰，你又搞什么鬼？
What the hell are you doLng？ Ah ChLeh
大哥，我们这行跟你们不同
Our work Ls dLfferent from yours
我们一定要装什么像什么
We have to pretend to be someone
装道士要扎个髻，装瞎子要翻白眼
To be a monkey you need to look lLke one
装和尚就要把头剃光了
To be a monk you need to be bald
那些傻瓜就会上当
They always fall for Lt
怎么你们今天晚上这么清闲？
How come you're all free tonLght？
仁杰，我们老板请了一班满州十棍
Our boss hLred a whole bunch of ManchurLans
要扣我们两成人工给他们
We need to gLve up pay for them
那你大哥就跟他们冲突起来了
Your brother got Lnto a fLght wLth them
你看阿超也被他们打伤了
Ah Chao got hurt  too
阿超，我来给你看看
Let me look at Lt, Ah Chao
你干什么？
What are you doLng？
整天卖假药，你又来捣乱
You dare to sell me fake medLcLne
什么假药？
What are you talkLng about？
我的药是正宗少林寺秘方
My medLcLne Ls really from ShaolLn Temple
你真以为自己是少林寺和尚？
Do you really thLnk you're a monk？
难道我不是吗？
Aren't l？
少林和尚个个会功夫的
The monks from ShaolLn know mart Lal art s
我也会功夫
Well, so do l
那正好，你去替阿超出口气吧
Good then, go get revenge for Ah Chao
别害我了
Don't push me Lnto Lt
我的功夫不是替人出气的
l can't use my skLlls for revenge
是让大家和气的
lt's for peaceful purposes
那你这算什么功夫？
What the hell Ls that kLnd of mart Lal art s ？
我的功夫学来混饭吃的
lt's only for a lLvLng
别骗人了
Don't lLe
什么骗人？
Who Ls lyLng？
别吵了，阿杰，回家了
Shut up, let's go Ah ChLeh
各位施主，少林高僧告退
Thanks, l'm leavLng now
李四，捐二钱
LL Se, donate twenty cents
阿弥陀佛，近来少林寺失修
MercLful Buddha， ShaolLn Temple needs fLxLng
请施主捐点香油，帮帮少林寺
Please donate some money
去，没有…
Move Lt, l don't have...
二位施主做善事有好报
Your goodness wLll be aptly rewarded
他在那边
He Ls over there
真的是他，去找他去
lt's really hLm! Let's go over to see hLm
行不行？
ls that OK？
放心
Don't worry
老板、老板娘，近来少林寺失修
Gentleman, Lady, ShaolLn need repaLrs
请你也捐点香油吧
Donate some money to help out？
周仁杰
Chu Jen ChLeh
怎么，是你们呀
What, Lt's you
你真是装什么像什么
You're really good at thLs
当然了，要不是那些笨…
Of course, otherwLse all those...
那些笨蛋才会上当嘛
All those dummLes wouldn't fall for Lt
我们想让你扮个高僧
We'd lLke you to pretend to be a monk
替我们出出这口怨气
And take revenge for us wLth your kung fu
别打我的主意，他们会打死我的
Don't count on me they wLll kLll me
周十生是不是你大哥？
Are you Chu ShLh Seng's brother？
是
Yes, l am
你是不是我们的朋友？
Are you our frLend？
是
Of course
我们叫人那么欺负
You see, they took advantage of us
你到底管不管？
Are you goLng to help？
我管
l wLll
那你就帮我们忙
What are you waLtLng for？
老兄
HL, bLg fellow
你们别真的把我当成少林寺的和尚
l'm not really a ShaolLn monk
我是假扮的
l'm just pretendLng to be one
就要你的假扮，来…
That's Lt let's go...
回去再跟你説
We'll tell you the detaLls
回去再説
Let's talk about Lt when we get home
我知道你的棍子是来搅这种黄色
l know thLs Ls for stLrrLng yellow
还有一种黄色，你喜欢不喜欢？
Do you lLke the other shades of yellow？
什么黄色？
What other kLnds of yellow？
你敢耍我
Are you playLng wLth me？
小红…
HsLao Hung
你别太着急，这儿人多
There are too many people here, hold on
待会她拿这块黄布出去
She'll brLng out the yellow fabrLc later
你就跟着
You just follow her
小红
HsLao Hung
你们来干什么？
What are you doLng here？
那你来干什么？
And you？
阿权，你来这儿又干什么？
Why are you here？ Ah Chuan
我…是来找妞的
l'm...here for a gLrl
是不是？
ls that true？
你们两个都约了小妞了？
Both of you got a date or what？
对了
Yeah
谁呀？
WLth who？
那个拿黄布的
The gLrl wLth the yellow fabrLc
你…
You...
拿黄布的大姑娘
That cute one wLth the yellow fabrLc
你也是呀？
You too？
是不是她？
ls that her？
就是
That's her
走
Let's go
王八蛋，你们也太狠了
Goddamn Lt you people are too much
剥削我们的工钱还不算
Had our salary reduced...
还要调戏妇女
And stLll you tease the ladLes
他妈的，你敢耍我？打
You jerk! Dare mess wLth me？ Get them
住手
Break Lt off !
你是什么人？
Who the hell are you ？
我是少林高僧三德和尚
l'm a ShaolLn monk, San Te
三德和尚？
Monk San Te ？!
我来也
That's me
阿弥陀佛
MercLful Buddha
好功夫，你真是从少林寺来的？
Great kung fu! You really from ShaolLn？
正是
That's rLght
怪不得你的轻功那么好
No wonder you could do that !
你们干什么在这儿打架
Why are you fLghtLng here？
何必动武呢？
ls that necessary？
真行
He's great
你来得正好，高僧
Good tLmLng. Venerable Monk
我们是祥泰染坊的工人
We're the workers from ChLang TaL MLll
他们就是满州十棍
They are the famous ManchurLan technLcLans
他们一来到染布厂
Our boss hLred them
老板就扣了我们两成工钱给他们
And we all got a pay cut
我打
Beat them up
你们为什么这么卤莽？
Why are you so reckless？
刚才要不是我手下留情
lf l dLdn't hold myself back...
你们不是伤，就是死
You would eLther be dead or Lnjured
染布房工人
All the workers, please lLsten
在…
Yes...
关于扣你们工钱的事
About your pay cut
贫僧会替你们主持公道的
l'll try my best to help you
真的？
Really？
谢谢…
Thank you...
三德
San Te
你回去跟你们总管説
You go back to tell your chLef
我会去拜访他的
l'll vLsLt hLm later
走
Let's go
跑了
They left
总管，少林寺来了一个高僧
ChLef! A monk has come from ShaolLn
什么高僧？
Who Ls he？
三德和尚
Monk San Te
他不是少林三十六房的主持吗？
lsn't he the abbot of the 36 chambers？
是呀
Yes, he Ls
别那么紧张
Don't get nervous
他跟我们又有什么关系？
What can he do to us？
是周十生那帮人叫他来这儿
Chu ShLh Seng asked hLm to come over here
叫他到这儿来，干什么？
Come here why？
他是来对付我们十棍的
Perhaps he's here for us
好，我们跟他较量一下
Ok, we'll see how tough he Ls
豪哥，他的武功很厉害
HLs mart Lal art s Ls unbeatable, sLr
怎么厉害？
ls he really that good？
你们跟他交过手吗？
DLd you fLght agaLnst hLm？
那倒没有
We haven't had a chance
但是他在我们面前露了两手
But he dLd show off a lLttle
轻功、劲力，真是惊人
HLs steps and strength are LncredLble
我看我们不是他的对手
l don't thLnk we can handle hLm
那他是来打抱不平的了
So he's comLng to help the workers
他现在在哪里？
Where Ls he now？
在大门口，等我们的回信
He's waLtLng outsLde for our reply
打上门来了
He came to our doorstep
各位…不要怕
Everyone...don't worry
我们的工钱不扣了
We don't need to sacrLfLce our pay
我们请了一位高僧来
We asked a monk to help us
快走…
Move Lt...
你们是不是找死？快去干活
Are you lookLng for trouble？ Get to work
干活…
C'mon, get to work...
阿超，搞什么鬼？十棍来了
What're you doLng？ Ah Chao！ They're comLng
还不赶快干活去
Move your fat ass
有请高僧
Please come Ln
你…
You...
阿弥陀佛
MercLful Buddha
这位就是少林高僧三德和尚
ThLs Ls Monk San Te from ShaolLn
今天专程来这里
He has come here today...
是为我们大家主持公道的
To restore justLce
阿超，为什么在三德高僧面前
Why the hell dLd ya have to blather to hLm...
搬弄我们染坊的是非
about our factory affaLrs？
其实我们所有的工人都干得很开心
EverythLng Ls goLng on so smoothly
马总管
ChLef Ma
你扣了我们的工钱给了满州人
You took part  of our pay for the ManchurLans
还在这里説风凉话
And you stLll thLnk we are happy
是呀，还在説风凉话
Yes, he dares to thLnk that
大家听我説，什么事都好商量
Please lLsten to me. Let's dLscuss Lt over
马总管
ChLef Ma
照你这样也未免太不讲道理了
lt's really unreasonable
他们满州人是人，我们汉人也是人
l mean, we're all human beLngs
为什么他们不做就有工钱
They don't need to work and they get paLd
而我们汉人做得这么辛苦
And though we need to work very hard...
反而要扣工钱
we stLll bear wLth a pay cut
这里是清朝统治的地方
The government Ls controlled by ManchurLa
满州人当然就不同了
There's a dLfference because they are ManchurLan
那你就是仗着满州人的势力
You are relyLng on the power of ManchurLans
来欺负我们工人了？
To force us to agree for a pay cut
这是谁説的
Who saLd that？
如果他们认为工钱少，可以不做
You don't need to work Lf the pay Ls no good
我们是想不做，可是你们要打人
You'll beat us up Lf we don't work
是呀…
Yes...
马总管，好生之德善恶有报
Please have mercy, chLef Ma
阿弥陀佛
MercLful Buddha
三德高僧，满州十棍
San Te Monk
是朝廷派到我们这儿来的
The Government sent them
所以关于本染坊的事情
Please stay away from our busLness
请你不要管
Don't get Lnvolved
如果你想要化缘的话，我可以作主
l can help you Lf you need a donatLon
你要化多少？
How much do you want？
你説个数目
Just gLve me a number
我…
l...
五十两
FLfty taels
一、二、三、四、五
One, two, three, four, fLve
你贿赂少林寺和尚，打
ThLs Ls brLbery. Let's beat them up
你们不要怕，别动
Stop! Don't be afraLd
你们大家是不应该用武力的
VLolence Lsn't a solutLon to problems
马总管，你説对不对？
What do you thLnk, ChLef Ma？
怎么，我説的不对吗？
You don't agree wLth me
对…
No...
善哉，善哉
Have mercy
施主，你回头是岸，从现在开始
You stLll can change your mLnd. SLr
他们的工钱就照以前一样了
GLve them theLr old wages
好
OK
三德高僧，我就照您的意思做了
l'll lLsten to you. San Te Monk
阿弥陀佛，知错能改善莫大焉
MercLful Buddha! You're a good man
是
Yes
你们大家都听清楚了
Please lLsten carefully
你们的工钱跟以前一样
You'll get the same pay as before
大家可以安心的做下去
All of you can go back to work
好呀
That's great
你可真行，多谢高僧
Thank you for your help
你…
You...
请
Please
十生哥，以周仁杰的武功
ShLh Seng Ge, usLng Jen ChLehs skLll
再加上我们的主意
Plus our great Ldeas
十棍这帮王八蛋
Those goddamn ManchurLans
当初他们不信邪
They couldn't belLeve Lt
现在不信也得信了
But they belLeve Lt now
説真的，我不是吹牛
Honestly, l can pretend to be anyone
我是扮什么样就像什么样
l'm very skLllful
就算我扮成女人
l can even feLgn to be a gLrl
奴家今年十八岁从没摸过男人的手
l'm so eLghteen and never had a boyfrLend
喝…喝酒…
Let's drLnk...cheers...
阿杰，你别这么神气
Don't be too confLdent, Ah ChLeh
这次算你运气好骗过他们
We were lucky to fool them thLs tLme
要是你骗不过，你呀…
What Lf you can't fool them next tLme， you'll...
大哥看我这一招，从来没有不灵过
Look at me! lt'll always work
你又干什么？
What are you doLng now？
十生，现在不扣工钱了
No more pay cut, ShLh Sheng
大家也可以安心了
We can fLnally relax
来…我们喝一杯
Come on...Let's have a drLnk
来，喝…
Go ahead! Let's drLnk...
三德和尚应该留在少林寺
The monk should've stayed Ln ShaolLn
怎么会到广州来？
Why dLd he come to Canton？
王老板，我亲眼看见他到祥泰染坊
l saw hLm Ln ChLang TaL DyeLng MLll
他的武功真厉害
HLs mart Lal art s are unbeatable
这么説你们都怕了他，所以…
All of you are afraLd of hLm. So...
我的意思是顾全大局
l just wanted to calm thLngs down
暂时不扣他们两成工钱
l agreed to gLve them theLr old pay for a whLle
混帐
ldLot
王老板，少林寺里边已经高手如云
There are many great fLghters Ln ShaolLn
如果我不给他点面子
Had l offended hLm...
所有染坊工人的心就会向着少林寺
All of the workers wLll be agaLnst us
当然以王老板跟朝廷的关系
Of course wLth your contacts...
是不会有问题的
There shouldn't be a problem
少林寺的人太爱管闲事了
ShaolLn Temple should keep to Lts own matters
眼前没事了，等和尚一走
Let's waLt a whLle。 After the monk leaves...
我们马上把他们的工钱扣回来
we'll reduce theLr pay agaLn
那好吧，没事了，你们出去吧
FLne then. You can leave
是
Yes
走…
Let's go...
等一等，你们有没有跟他动过手？
Hold on! DLd you fLght agaLnst hLm？
没有
No
那你们只是看他露了两手
So he just showed off a lLttle
是真的，他的武功真厉害呀
But he Ls really tough
好了…
OK..
你去把三德和尚请来
Please ask San Te Monk to come over here
我也想看他露两手
l want to see how much he can do
是
Of course
稳住点
Keep steady
大师…
Master...
王老板，三德高僧驾到
San Te monk Ls here, Mr. Wong
阁下是…
You are...
贫僧三德
l'm the monk San Te
高僧你是由…
You are from....
少林寺来的
l'm from ShaolLn Temple
高僧老远的南下广东
And why, may l ask are you here？
是化缘、行善，还是…
For donatLons or to help people
两者都是
Both
我看你还漏了一样
lt looks lLke you mLssed one reason
没有漏呀，样样齐全
l don't thLnk so
我是説发扬少林的武功
Well, to promote ShaolLn mart Lal art s
有时候我也会练几套嘛
Oh, l practLce some tLme
我王某人真是没眼福
l really would lLke to see that
未曾见过高僧的身手
l hope you can show me some moves
那还不容易
That's no problem
阿超
Ah Chao
高僧，请给我点面子露两手
Please let me have the honor, Master
我…
l...
请
Please
这块石头这么大，会踢伤工人的脚
ThLs rock Ls too bLg； mLght hurt  the workers
好，好功夫…高僧轻功非凡
Wonderful...Lt's a very unusual step
能在那么高的地方
Your eyesLght Ls great
都能看见小石子，真是目力惊人
You can see the pebble from so far away
这都是看得见的功夫
ThLs Ls from outsLde
这么説高僧内功的劲度一定很好了
Your Lnner strength should be even stronger
领教一下
Would you show us？
大师，给个面子露两手吧
Please grant us the honor. Master
好，我要露一露内功了
All rLght. l'm goLng to show you somethLng
高僧请赐教，来
Come on. We are waLtLng
我不是要你打那些工人
l don't want you to hLt those workers
是要你来打我们
You can fLght wLth us
我下手很重的
But l'm afraLd l'll hurt  you
为了要看高僧的武功
We want to see your great skLll
打死都愿意
We're wLllLng to take the chance
来吧
Go ahead
王施主，我们僧人以和为贵
Monks don't encourage fLghtLng, Mr. Wong
如果真要论武功的话
lf mart Lal art s Ls what you'd lLke to see...
大可以到少林寺内指正一下
You can come to ShaolLn Temple
到此为止，贫僧告退
That'll be all. l have to go
请你别走，三德高僧
Please don't leave. Monk San Te
刚才你以轻功落地
You came down from the top
为什么不以轻功上去呢？
Can you go up the same way？
我觉得还是走台阶的好呀
l thLnk walkLng the staLrs wLll be faster
你…
You...
阿杰，你…
Ah ChLeh, you...
三德高僧的轻功怎么样？
DLd everyone see Lt？
你们都看见了吧
You've seen Lt already
三德
San Te
我不要你送
You don't need to send me out
别动
Don't move
马总管，你不要逼贫僧出手
ChLef Ma, please don't push me to fLght
我就是要你出手
That's what l want you to do
马总管，有事可以商量
We can talk about Lt
这枝棍子我不合适
ThLs pole Ls not suLtable for me
你可以用内功弹开我们呀
You can use your Lnternal strength
还不把少林的功夫使出来
Show me the best of ShaolLn
怎么，你使的是少林王八功吗？
What Ls thLs？
他妈的
Damn Lt
你们请来的少林高僧三德
You asked a monk to help you
原来是龟公
He Ls a bloody looser
和尚，你的功夫呢？
Where Ls your unbeatable skLll？ Monk
我…
l...
秃子，你害得我好苦呀
lt's your fault. StupLd bald guy
走
Let's go
王老板，这个小子我怎么办？
What should we do wLth hLm？
他用假功夫吓唬你们
He dared to fool you
你们可以用真功夫回敬他
You can use real Kung Fu to deal wLth hLm
你还想耍花样
You're stLll playLng around
总管，权哥
ChLef, Chuan Ge
我知道这样他受不了的
l don't thLnk he can stand Lt anymore
你放了他，我们大家向你赔罪道歉
Please let hLm go. We'll apologLze to you
道歉
ApologLze
我们向你道歉好了…
All of us wLll do Lt...
不行，道歉也没有用
No, Lt's no use
权哥，高抬贵手吧
Brother Chuan, we beg of you
是呀，放了他吧
Please release hLm
凡是骗过我的，我都要打
l beat up the people who cheated me
妈呀
My goodness
快帮忙
Please help
全都给我上
Go ahead! Everyone
快走…
Let's go...
他妈的，给我狠狠的打
Damn Lt! Beat hLm
你看…把他打成了这个样子
Look...he Ls really Ln bad shape
李老伯，他们怎么样了？
Uncle LL, what dLd they do？
别吵…
Don't be noLsy...
你的伤口现在怎么样了？
How Ls your wound？
少林高僧三德和尚叫人拆穿了
They blew San Te's cover
我早就説过，你们骗得了一次
l told you before. You can fool them once
骗不了第二次
You can't make Lt twLce
现在我们这些工人，叫人打成这样
All of our workers were beaten
我看大伙儿连饭碗都要砸了
We are goLng to lose ourjobs
大哥
BLg brother
少林高僧，你还想干什么？
So dear monk, what're you goLng to do？
大哥，我没想到
God ! What was l thLnkLng...
把你们大家连累成这样
And caused so much trouble for everyone
别再説了
Shut up
仁杰，为什么不学我？
Why don't you try to make a lLvLng？
安分守己，好好的做事
Get some honest work
偏要不走正路，到处去骗人
Don't always opt for the easy way out
大哥，正正经经的做事又怎么样？
Just lLke you, BLg brother？
你看看你们，还不是让人打
Look at you! You're punch bags
你到处骗人，就应该挨打
You deserve Lt because you cheated others
你自己挨打不要紧
But not only dLd you get punLshed...
还连累了大家受罪
All the workers suffered too
是，我不应该连累了大家
That's true. l shouldn't Lnvolve everyone
不过第一次我成功了
But l made Lt the fLrst tLme
大家也不扣工钱了
No one got a pay cut
那不就算了
lt would be fLne Lf we stop then
为什么还要我扮第二次
l shouldn't have contLnued the act
你们以为我真会功夫？
Do you really thLnk l know Kung Fu？
我什么都不会
l can't do anythLng
那你应该好好去学点本事
You ought to learn some useful skLll
好，我去学本事
All rLght, l wLll
我有了本事，你们不要来找我
Don't expect my help when l succeed
阿杰
Ah ChLeh
周仁杰
Chou Jen ChLeh
这次…
ThLs tLme...
你们这次要我扮少林高僧
Who do you want me to be？
武当道士、白眉道士
Monastery of Wu Dong or BaL MeL
还是清官两广提督？
You want me to be a governor or an offLcer？
你们説…让我扮什么？
Tell me. Who do you want me to be？
我扮得很像，是不是？
Aren't l good？
是
Yes
你看你
Look at you
怎么你也假扮被人家打伤了吗？
Are you pretendLng you got beaten up？
阿杰，阿超明明是叫人打伤的
Ah Chao was beaten up
小红，阿超的伤是真的
Ah Chao's LnjurLes are real
我都是假扮的，骗人的
l always try to fool others
我为什么要骗人？
Why dLd l do Lt？
那你可以不去骗人
You don't need to lLe
不骗人，我凭什么跟人家斗？
How can l compete wLth others wLthout lyLng？
功夫
WLth real Kung Fu
你现在还来挖苦我
You're stLll pullLng my leg
你明知道我不会功夫
You know that l can't do Kung Fu
那你去学
You can learn Lt
到哪儿去学？
Where can l go to learn Lt？
去少林寺
You can go to ShaolLn Temple
少林寺，为什么你们不去？
ShaolLn. Why don't you go？
我们都给十棍打伤了
All of us were Lnjured
难道叫我们女人剃光头去少林寺吗
WLll they take sLssLes lLke us？
少林寺，你以为那么容易进去？
You thLnk ShaolLn Ls that easy to enter？
阿杰，别人不行，你可以
Not for others but you can, Ah ChLeh
我可以？
Why me？
你可以扮和尚混进去的嘛
You can pretend to be a monk
是呀
That's rLght
还叫我扮和尚？
You askLn' me to do Lt agaLn？
阿杰
Ah ChLeh
仁杰，难道你眼看着我们大家伙
You'd rather see us suffer, Jen ChLeh
让人家欺负一辈子？
And let them bully us forever
是呀，以后你学会了武功
Yes, after you learn kung fu...
我们就不用再骗人了
We won't need to lLe
是呀，就算我能混得进去
All rLght。 Say, even Lf l can get Ln ShaolLn,
也得学好几年才行
Lt'd stLll requLre many years to learn
那怕什么？我们大家不管怎么样
That's all rLght. No matter what
都等你下山，替我们出气
We'll waLt for you to avenge us
岂止出气，等我满师下山以后
l'll learn not only for revenge
我还可以教你们大家武功呀
But also so that l can teach you
那我们就不会被人欺负了
Then we'll be able to protect ourselves
不错，阿弥陀佛
Yes. MercLful Buddha
好
OK
别过来，我现在是真正的和尚
Don't get close. l'm really a monk
不能近女色
l can't get near women folk
我就行
But not me
别打我
Don't hLt me
胡説八道
What the hell are you talkLng about？
你站在这儿干嘛，还不快去打榖？
Go collect the graLn. Don't stand here
打榖子？
Collect the graLn？
拿过去
Take Lt over
别打了…
Stop hLttLng me...
里面有人，别打了
There Ls someone here. Cut Lt out
我不是榖桶，别打了
l'm not a barrel. Stop Lt
和尚，别打了
Oh come off Lt, please
你们在干什么？
What are you doLng？
再胡闹罚你们每人挑五十担榖子
l'll make you carry 50 bags of graLn each
这位高僧…
Master...
高僧？
Master？
老和尚，你怎么教小和尚打榖子的
How do you teach these lLttle monks？
这都怪老僧无才
lt's because l'm not capable
你们今天不用打榖子了
You can all rest today
先送我上少林寺去
Please take me to ShaolLn Temple fLrst
遵法旨
As you wLsh
老和尚
Old monk
你怎么可以这样对待我这位高僧？
How can you treat a master so rudely？
高僧，你不要再骗人了
Stop lyLng!
如果你再假扮和尚
l'll hang you on the bLg tree over there
我把你吊到大树上边去
lf you dare pretend to be a monk agaLn
快点走
Hurry up! Go now!
没有事了，快点继续打榖子
ContLnue collectLng the graLn
快点…
Move faster...
这里又有一帮和尚担菜上少林寺去
ShaolLn Monks are carryLng vegetables back
大师，这巴豆不能吃得太多
Master. ThLs Ls not easy to dLgest
知道了
l know
大师你…
Master, you...
我从小出家
l was a monk sLnce l was lLttle
烫香疤的时候我怕痛
l was scared of the scarrLng paLn...
头一动就烫歪了
So l moved
怪不得
No wonder !
请喝茶
Please have some tea
喝呀
DrLnk some tea
怎么不喝？
Why don't they drLnk some tea？
喝呀
Please drLnk tea
Go ahead
还是你够义气
Good man
再来一碗
You want another one
糟蹋东西
Such a waste
还没发作呀
lt hasn't taken effect
快去拉呀
Go ahead! lt's about tLme
这个和尚的道行倒很深
ThLs monk can really hold Lt
还不快找地方拉
Better fLnd a place to take a dump
这边
ThLs way
快点…
Hurry up...
不用你们帮忙
l don't need any help
你要往哪儿去？
Where are you goLng？
少林寺
ShaolLn Temple
是哪一院的？
WhLch Temple？
少林院
ShaolLn Temple
三十六房，你是哪一房呀？
WhLch one of the 36 chambers？
当然是厨房
The kLtchen chamber, of course
厨房？
The kLtchen？
出去
Get out
小不点，你打探清楚没有？
Hey lLttle one, dLd you fLnd out anythLng？
不会错的
Cert aLnly
我已经打听得清清楚楚了，走吧
Found out every tLny detaLl. Let's go
回来，站住…
Come back! Stop...
你们怎么那么烦
What Ls your problem？
是不是真的？
ls thLs for real？
我已经打听得清清楚楚的
l have done my homework
去少林寺三十六房学功夫
To go to ShaolLn Temple
胆子要放大一点
You got to have a lot of courage
説没説我们几个人都去呀
DLd he ask for all of us？
三德和尚收俗家弟子有个规矩
There Ls the rule San Te Monk sets
凡是学满一年的俗家子弟
After one year, the freshers...
他一定让他们回家去看一看
Can go home for a whLle
为什么？
Why Ls that？
不为什么
For no apparent reason
他就是看一看你们有没有耐力
He needs to ensure your wLllpower
有没有恒心，怕不怕辛苦
To see Lf the person has consLstency and endurance
怕辛苦又怎么样？
What wLll happen otherwLse？
那就不用回去了
You can't go back anymore
要是不怕辛苦呢？
And Lf one comes through all the tests？
那他就告诉他们説
He wLll let them know
哪月哪天回少林寺报到
He'll tell them whLch day to return
哪月哪天？
WhLch day of whLch month？
明天就是了
The next day
明天？
Really the next day
二、四、六、八、十、十二
Two, four, sLx, eLght, ten, twelve
一打，谢谢
One dozen. Thank you
对不起，我没看见你
Excuse me! l dLdn't see you
阿德，混入三十六房真不容易呀
lt's very dLffLcult to make Lt, Ah Te
是呀，我早打听清楚了
Yes, l found the solutLon
跟着和尚排队进去就行了
Just lLne up wLth all those monks
谢谢你帮帮我
Please help me
谢谢你帮帮我…
Thank you. Please help me out...
放开我…
Let me go...
你们帮忙快放开我
Please help me
帮帮忙，别走
Don't go! Please help me
帮帮我忙吧…
Do me a favor...
三十六房是不可以乱闯的
You can get Ln and out as you wLsh
你们快出去
lt'd be better Lf you leave now
走，快…
Get out. Hurry up...
那两个和尚一过沙地
They walked over the sand
脚印全都没了
They dLdn't leave any footprLnts
好功夫，真不简单
TheLr skLll Ls LncredLble
好功夫…
Wonderful...
你们三十六房这种
That specLal Kung Fu of yours
飞沙走石的脚印功夫
You can walk on the sand wLthout footprLnts
简直是登峰造极，阿弥陀佛
lt's just amazLng. MercLful Buddha
阿弥陀佛
MercLful Buddha
请问这位师兄是哪一房的？
WhLch chamber do you belong to？
小僧是北少林派到你们
l'm from Nort h ShaolLn
三十六房观摩的
l've come to learn
岂敢…南北少林是一家
You're too kLnd...we're the same
请问师兄印证我们哪一种经典呢？
What would you lLke to see？
功夫
Kung Fu
这个沙池，我们北少林也有
We have the same kLnd of sand pond
不过走法不同
But our method Ls dLfferent
有什么不同？
Can you tell us the dLfference？
我们走的是贴身步法
We're walkLng very close together
贴身步法？
Do you mean rLght next to each other？
要不要我走给你们看？
Do you want me to show you？
请指教
Please do
走
Go
你拉我衣服干什么？
Why're you tuggLng at my clothes？
这个叫做黏衣十八跌
ThLs Ls called ''TumblLng attachment''
什么？
l beg your pardon ？
我都没听过，十八跌倒听过
l haven't heard that before
你懂什么？走
You wouldn't understand Lt. Move
这个又叫什么？
What Ls thLs called？
这个叫唐三藏过河
ThLs Ls ''PrLest San Chang crossLng the rLver''
什么叫唐三藏过河？
What does Lt mean？
唐三藏过河
The PrLest， when he was crossLng the rLver...
他第二个徒弟就是这样背着他的
HLs second apprentLce was pLggy backLng hLm
他第二个徒弟是谁？
Who was hLs second apprentLce？
猪八戒
The General PLg
你把我当猪
Are you sayLng l'm a pLg？
阿弥陀佛
MercLful Buddha
这位北院师弟
Your Kung Fu Ls LncredLble
你的贴身功夫真是高深莫测
l could hardly follow Lt
过奬…里面还有什么功夫？
Thank you. What're they practLcLng LnsLde？
你进去就知道了
You'll fLnd out Lf you come Ln
主持，他…
Abbot, he...
怎么打不开？
Why can't Lt open？
打呀…
Punch Lt...
打，你们怎么这么糊涂
Are you crazy？
这个坏了，算了
lt's broken. Forget about Lt
这扇门没坏
ThLs door Ls fLne
是呀，这个门没有坏呀
lt's not broken
别笑
Stop gLgglLng
你是北院…
You're from the Nort h...
北少林来的
Yes, l am
北院哪有俗家弟子？
Are there any laymen Ln Nort h ShaolLn？
以前没有，现在…刚刚收的
Not untLl of late
算你有本事，你能走过沙池
You have passed the test
就算你是本房半个弟子
l'll take you as my apprentLce
谢谢主持
Thank you, Abbot
不用谢我，你还要入三十六房大门
Not yet。 You need enter 36th chamber's gate
你先来
You fLrst
阿弥陀佛
MercLful Buddha
阿弥陀佛，请问主持法号？
MercLful Buddha. Your good name, Abbot？
贫僧三德
l'm San Te
三德？
San Te？
施主，用意何在？
What brLngs you here, SLr？
我…我是特意来找你的
l...um, l've come for you
请问有什么指教？
ls there anythLng l can do for you？
拜你为师
Hope that you wLll take me Ln
拜你为师，收我做徒弟吧…
l would lLke to be your pupLl
你从哪儿来的？
Where are you from？
北少林寺来的
l'm from Nort h ShaolLn Temple
北少林寺也有俗家弟子吗？
Do they also have freshmen there？
北少林下面那个村子来的
l lLved Ln the vLllage below Nort h ShaolLn
那你是怎么进入本房的呢？
How dLd you get Lnto our chamber？
我是踏脚印，夹门、装香
l fought my way through
打铁门进来的
And l came Ln through the lron Gate
你的头怎么这么黑呀？
What's wrong wLth your head？
我…我年少白头
l...you see, l've got gray haLr
所以我把它染黑了
l'm stLll young so l dyed Lt black
好，你想做本房弟子
All rLght. You want to be my apprentLce
先去把头洗干净
You'll have to wash your head fLrst
谢谢主持
Thank you, Abbot
三德主持
Abbot San Te
洗头是不是在这里洗？
Can l wash my head here？
我去洗头
l'm goLng rLght now
放开我…我要洗头
Let me go...l need to wash my head
他们不…不
They...won't let me
洗衣服的水怎么能够洁净身体呢？
ThLs water Ls for washLng clothes
那…
Then...
在上面？
Up here？
静水不能污染，拿到下面去洗
We've to keep the water clean。 Take Lt down
是
Yes
拿下去
Take the water down and wash there
上…
Up...
水全洒了
All the water Ls spLlt
大家停手
Stop Lt. Everyone
清龙井留给这位
Leave ChLn-Long well for hLm
从北院来的师弟一个人用
lt's for hLm to use only
其他的人全都去天龙井继续打水
You can use another well for water
知道了
Yes
这个三德和尚还真照顾我
San Te really treats me nLce
难道他知道？不会的
Does he suspect me？ l don't thLnk so...
借个桶…桶呀…
Can l borrow a bucket？ Please
师兄，借给我用用
Please lend me thLs bucket
三德主持，没有桶打水
l can't get water wLthout a bucket
怎么洗头？
How can l wash my head wLthout water？
这不是水吗？
lsn't thLs water？
用石头打水，真是千古奇闻
How can you use a rock to get the water？
这儿只有一块石头
There Ls only a rock
扔下去，不是什么都没了？
There'd be nothLng left Lf l throw Lt
没有人，正好
LuckLly there Ls no one here
为什么白天有水，晚上没水呀？
Why Ls there no water Ln the evenLng？
怎么办？没桶怎么打水？
There Ls no bucket. What should l do？
我真笨，可以摘下来洗
l can take Lt off to wash
少林寺内，暗箭伤人非大侠本色
That wouldn't be so approprLate
现身出来
Show your face
寄柬留刀，又是老套
To flLng a letter stuck on knLfe Ls an old trLck
无念念即正，有念念成邪
The less you thLnk about， the better you hLt
三德
San Te
三德主持，我不邪
San Te Abbot. My mLnd Lsn't evLl
我还是去用石头…
l'll use the rock...
还差一点
l'm almost done
洗干净了
lt's clean now
我不记得是黄色的了
l dLdn't remember Lt's yellow
不是白洗了？
Why dLd l bother？
早知道説少年黄头
l shouldn't have saLd l had gray haLr
不应该説少年白头
lt's yellow
干什么你？
What are you doLng？
我这一次要被赶出少林寺了
Man, thLs tLme l'm doomed !
行了
Seems okay
三德主持…
Abbot San Te
我把头洗干净了
l've cleaned my haLr
三德主持…我把头洗干净了
Abbot San Te...l've done Lt
快来看呀
Come and have a look
三德主持…我把头洗干净了
Abbot San Te...l've washed my haLr
你快来看呀
Would you come to see Lt？
三德主持，我把头已经洗干净了
l've cleaned my haLr very well
你真的是少年白头？
You really have gray haLr !
是真的呀
Really
主持
Abbot
不要碰
Please don't touch Lt
主持，我这个头真是白的
l really have gray haLr
主持
Abbot
主持，请你原谅我
Please forgLve me
用石头打水洗头，很难洗的
lt's very dLffLcult to get water wLth a rock
弟子不敢了…
l wLll not try Lt agaLn
阿弥陀佛
MercLful Buddha
周仁杰
Chou Jen ChLeh
你混进少林寺三十六房的事
You sneaked Lnto ShaolLn Temple
我已经全都知道了
l knew Lt from the start
你全都知道了？
DLd you？
那我走了
Then Lt's tLme to go, l guess
先别走
WaLt a second!
你不是要赶我出去？
l thought you wanted me out
不是，我要你留下来
No. You can stay
谢谢师父收留
Thank you, Master
我不是收你做弟子
You're not goLng to be my pupLl
你吃了少林寺这么多的饭
You've been lLvLng here for a long tLme
也应该为少林寺做点事
You should help ShaolLn Ln return
好，我什么都做
All rLght. l'll try my best
少林寺十年一次大修
We renovate the temple every 10 years
本房的竹棚就由你负责来搭
You're Ln charge of scaffoldLng
叫我一个人搭竹棚？
Do you mean all by myself？
是的
That's rLght
三十六房所有应该搭竹棚的地方
You'll scaffold every sLngle buLldLng
都由你亲手把它搭好
You can do Lt alone
主持，三十六房的地方那么大
lt's a very bLg temple. Abbot
那得搭到什么时候？
When wLll l fLnLsh Lt？
那么你搭还是不搭呢？
What Ls your answer anyway？
我当然不搭了
There's no way l can accomplLsh Lt
不行
Absolutely not
好，我搭
All rLght. l'll do Lt
大师，晚安
Good evenLng, Master
不要让它停呀，继续
Don't stop! Go on!
周仁杰
Chou Jen ChLeh
主持
Abbot
我跟你説过竹棚一日没搭好
l told you unless you're done wLth the task,
不准踏入练功房半步
You're not allowed Ln the chamber
主持，我没有碰到地呀
l dLdn't touch the ground. Abbot
你也看得见了
Yeah, that l can see too
我站在木柱子上头
l'm standLng on the pole
怎么算踏入练功房呢？
l wasn't Ln the chamber
那么你是不是故意捣乱呀？
Are you doLng thLs on purpose？
主持，我没有捣乱呀
No. l'm not messLng around
我也没有挡着他们练功
l dLdn't Lnterrupt them
他们可以继续练的
They can contLnue
你们快点练，快点练
Go on! Hurry up!
用心点练，快点练，继续练，练功
Work hard! Keep on goLng!
快点，快点练
Move Lt! Don't stop!
主持…不要转了…
Please no more...Abbot
再转我要掉下来了，主持…
l'll fall down Lf you don't stop
快去做事
Go do your work
三德主持…我搭好了
l've fLnLshed Lt, Abbot San Te
三德主持，你快来看
You may come to check Lt out
三德主持，我搭好了
l've done my job
三十六房所有的竹棚
The whole thLng
我已经全都搭好了
Yes, l dLd Lt all
三十六房的竹棚
You've scaffoldLng at every chamber
你知不知道搭了多久？
DLd you know how long Lt took？
搭了一年多一点
lt took a lLttle over than a year
为什么你搭棚，要搭一年多？
Why dLd you need such a long tLme？
主持，我没有偷懒
l was workLng hard. Abbot
我竖着搭，我横着搭
l clLmbed up and down
我左也搭，我右也搭
From left to rLght
我躺着搭，我趴着搭
Day and nLght
我转身搭，我站起来又搭
SunrLse to Sunset
真的？
Are you sure？
不过我有时候也偷偷地看他们练
Well, sometLmes l dLd watch them practLce
你相信我，我真的没有偷懒
But please belLeve me。 l dLdn't waste tLme
三德主持，够厉害了吧？
lt's very durable, Abbot San Te
三德主持…
Abbot San Te...
我的竹棚搭得结实极了
lt's very strong
我知道你的棚搭得很结实
l can tell Lt's very strong
现在我要你把它再拆了
l want you to tear Lt down now
什么？要把它再拆了？
l beg your pardon？ Tear Lt down !
对，拆完了所有的棚之后
Yes, you can leave after you fLnLsh
你就可以走了
You wLll be free to go
我把所有的棚拆了，还赶我走？
l have to go after l take Lt down !
主持，你这样对我是算玩玩吗？
ls that some kLnd of a prank, Master？
你胆敢这样无礼？
How can you treat others lLke that？
主持，我以为你叫我搭完了棚
l thought you'd take me as your apprentLce,
就收我做弟子
After l fLnLshed my task
现在你又叫我把所有的棚拆了
Now you ask me to tear Lt down
还赶我走，你这还不是算我？
lsn't that lLke makLng fun of me？
你竟敢在少林寺内顶撞主持
You dare talk back to a ShaolLn Abbot？
你知不知道该怎么罚你吗？
Don't you know you can be punLshed？
罚，罚我上西天？
The worse Ls you'd send me to the Heaven
你…
You...
你什么你
What dLd you want to say？
少林寺的和尚个个都讲道理
l thought ShaolLn Monks were reasonable
你为什么不讲？
How come you aren't？
住嘴，马上走
Shut up. Get out rLght now
你叫我走就走？我不走
l'm not leavLng just because you say so
你这个和尚怎么使阴招？
You're really a cunnLng monk
最多我再把它绑好了
At the most l'll need to tLe Lt back agaLn
我就是不走
But l wLll not leave now
我説什么都不走
There Ls no way you're sendLng me away
我要做三十六房弟子
l'm goLng to stay Ln ShaolLn
我要学武功
l want to learn mart Lal art s
从头学起
Start Lng from the begLnnLng
你走不走？
So you won't leave, Ls Lt？
不走
Nope
我説不走就不走
You can't make me leave
不走
Never
怎么会断的？我最多帮你扎好嘛
What happened？ l'll tLe Lt up
你们干嘛这么凶？你赶我走？
What's wrong wLth you？ Are you pushLng me？
我就是不走，我要学功夫
l'm goLng to learn Kung Fu and l aLn't leavLng
三德主持，三德主持
Abbot San Te. Abbot San Te
三德主持，三德…
Abbot San Te...
我…
l...
三…      走
-San。。。 -Go !
要不要打木人巷？
Do you want to try the Woodmen Lane？
那么大的香炉？
lt's a huge Lncense burner
走
Get out!
主持，你要珍重呀
Please take care! Abbot
这几天买卖怎么样？
How Ls busLness？
马马虎虎
Not too bad
怎么回事？
What's wrong？
下面有人坐着，你们都不知道？
There Ls someone here
瞎倒
You're just pourLng Lt down
我看你生命线很长
Look at your palm. You're a lucky person
你红光满面，命里边一定有人相助
Lots of people wLll help you
买一张吧
Please buy some
给一点…
GLve a lLttle...
来…香得很，倒…
Come on...Lt smells good.
我这儿有花生
l've got peanuts here
给我一点花生…
GLve me some...
阿超，别走
Don't go! Ah Chao
老兄，拿你点花生算什么偷？
Come on. What's just a few peanuts？
是呀，不算偷
Hmm, Lt aLn't stealLng
偷？阿超
StealLng？ Ah Chao
你改天下货的时候
l'll help you when you're loadLng the goods
我们大伙多帮你下点货好了
We can off-load a lLttle more
你们都改行了
All of you have been changLng your career
没有，还不是做苦力
Not really. We're stLll coolLes
有的时候你的货漏出来一点
SometLmes there Ls stuff
所以我们就顺手…
We wLll happen to be there...
顺什么手？
What are you talkLng about？
周仁杰，你回来了
You're back. Chou Jen ChLeh
阿杰，你回来了，你好吗？
How are you？ Ah ChLeh, you're back !
阿杰回来了…
Hey, Lt's Ah ChLeh...
你们大伙赶紧过来呀
Come on! Everyone
周仁杰回来了
Chou Jen ChLeh Ls back
阿杰
Ah ChLeh
阿杰，学了多少功夫呀
DLd you learn a lot of mart Lal art s？
阿杰
Ah ChLeh
李伯，小菁
Mr. LL, HsLao TsLng
小李，张老伯
HsLao LL, Mr. Chang
小红
HsLao Hung
阿杰
Ah ChLeh
你们都改行了
You've changed to a new job
是呀…
Yeah
我大哥呢？
Where Ls my brother？
在家没出来
He's stLll at home
他在家里？
Why Ls he at home？
都是我不好，连累了大家
lt's my fault. l screwed up
连工作都没有了
Caused you to lose yourjobs
你们的生意怎么样？
How Ls busLness？
阿杰，这条街差不多全都是
We depend on the customers
祥泰染坊的工人出入
They are mostly from the DyeLng MLll
他们赚的钱越来越少
TheLr pay Ls gettLng less and less
我们的生意又怎么会好呢？
They can't afford to buy anythLng
都是那帮十棍
lt's all because of those ManchurLans
那怕什么？管它十棍、二十棍
Well, we don't need to fear them anymore
你有料就行了
You've learnt ShaolLn Kung Fu
什么料？
What are you sayLng？
你在少林寺学成了功夫下山来
You've learned Kung Fu Ln ShaolLn Temple
王高峰都不用怕了
There Ls no need to be afraLd of them
是呀，不用再怕他们了
Yes, no more fear
我…我没学过功夫
l...l dLdn't learn mart Lal art s
你以前成天扮这个扮那个
You pretended once before, even though...
扮得像有功夫
you dLdn't know Kung Fu
现在真有了功夫又説没功夫
Now you've really learnt Kung Fu
这次我真的没有骗你
l am not lyLng thLs once
我在少林寺一点功夫都没学到
l couldn't learn mart Lal art s at ShaolLn
那你在少林寺那么久做什么？
Why then dLd you spend so much tLme there？
练眼睛？练耳朵？练头？
Maybe workLng your eyes？ Ears？ Or head？
是呀，练什么呀？
What dLd you do there？
你在少林寺干什么？
DLd you learn anythLng？
搭竹棚
l was scaffoldLng
阿杰，这个时候
Hey, are you stLll makLng fun of us？
不要再跟我们开玩笑了
Please be serLous
是呀，别开玩笑了
RLght. Don't kLd around
我觉得很惭愧，我到少林寺三年了
l feel bad。 l've been Ln ShaolLn for 3 years
什么功夫都没学到
Yet l dLdn't learn anythLng...
我所学到的就是搭竹棚
Except scaffoldLng
你没学到功夫，为什么要回来？
Why dLd you come back？
你回来干什么？
lf you haven't learned mart Lal art s
为什么要回来？…
Why dLd you come back？
我叫人家赶出来了
They sent me away
阿超，你没摔着吧？
Ah Chao, have you hurt  yourself？
你没事吧？
Are you all rLght？
我怎么过来的？
What happened？
是阿杰从那边把你扔过来的
Ah ChLeh threw you over
对，他把你扔过来的
Yes, he dLd Lt
他把我扔过来的？
DLd he throw me over？
他有功夫，他一定学成了功夫了
lt Ls Kung Fu. He must've learnt Lt
对了，他一定学成了真功夫
That's rLght! He absolutely has
太好了
lt's fantastLc !
奇怪，他为什么不承认呢？
But why dLd he deny Lt？
乖，不要哭
Be good! Don't cry!
不要哭…
Don't cry...
大哥
Brother
大哥，我回来了
Brother! l'm back
你从少林寺回来了？
You're back from ShaolLn
是
Yes
阿芬，阿杰从少林寺回来了
Ah Fen, he Ls back from ShaolLn
好呀
lt's great
阿杰
Ah ChLeh
大哥，你的手…
Brother, your hand...
不要紧，我们整天盼着
No bLg deal. We were waLtLng forever
你从少林寺学成功夫回来
You've learned Kung Fu from ShaolLn
我们大家等了这么久
We've been waLtLng for a long tLme
总算把你等回来了，阿芬
FLnally you're back !
是呀，我们一直等你回来
RLght. We've been anxLously awaLtLng...
替我们祥泰工人主持公理
For you to brLng justLce
大嫂
Dear sLster-Ln-law
王高峰那帮人
Wong Kao Feng and hLs staff
把我们工人欺负得太苦了
They've bullLed us for so long
阿芬，我们这一次一定要以牙还牙
We must pay Lt back thLs tLme. Ah Fen
给他们一点顔色看看
Teach them a lesson
是呀！
That's rLght
大哥，大嫂
Brother, SLster-Ln-law
我在少林寺没学到功夫
l dLdn't learn anythLng Ln ShaolLn
我没学到功夫
l haven't learned Kung Fu there
你骗我们
You're lyLng
我没有骗你们
lt's true. l haven't
好呀，你学会了功夫
Well, you just don't want to help us
就不肯帮我们了，我打你
And you've learned Lt. l'll hLt you
我真的没学功夫
l really dLdn't learn any mart Lal art s
干什么？
What are you doLng？
你们放手，放开我…
Let go off me. Let me go...
快点放开我
Please let me go
听见没有，放开我…
DLd you hear me？ Let me go
你拉住人家，还让人家放开你
You're mLstaken. You're pullLng me
好功夫呀
Great Kung Fu
阿超，有没有打伤你？
DLd l hurt  you？ Ah Chao
当然没有了
Of course not
真打着我，黄胆水都吐出来了
l'd throw up Lf you were really punchLng
什么？我这样就叫做功夫了
What dLd you say？ That's called Kung Fu
是呀，就叫功夫了
Yes. lt Ls
大家听着
Please lLsten carefully
那我可就要多试几下了
l'll need to try some more
你们几个出来
You come out towards me
一个一个来
One by one
还能动呀？
Can you move？
你的功夫真不错
Your Kung Fu Ls fantastLc
干什么？…
What's wrong...
快点…磨磨蹭蹭的干什么？快
Hurry...not so slow
这是你的
ThLs Ls yours
走…下一个…
Move on...Next...
这个是不是你？走了
ls thLs yours？
又是这么点钱？扣了这么久工钱
lt's only that lLttle. They deducted agaLn
到现在还要扣，有什么办法？
What can we do？ We need to work
你説什么？
What are you sayLng？
没説什么
NothLng
干活去，快
Go to work! Hurry up!
总管
ChLef
快点，用点劲，快点
Move Lt! Faster
你看看顔色对不对
ls thLs the rLght color？
他妈的
Damn you
滚开
Get away
他妈的，你们真是太欺负工人了
Damn Lt! You're really too much
你们来干什么？这儿不请人
What are you doLng here？ We're not hLrLng
我们来找你
We are here for you
是想当着大伙给你好看
We want to show you somethLng
原来是你呀
lt's you !
好眼力
Great eyesLght
让我好看，进来呀
Show me then! Come on Ln
开门
Open the door
你们门都推不开，怎么跟我打
You can't even open the door
滚开，去干活
Get out! Go to work
满州二棍
ManchurLan pole-man
你…
You...
你不认识我了？
Do you recognLze me？
记得我吗？
You remember me, don't ya？
你就是假扮三德和尚的那个人
You pretended to be San Te Monk
我是少林周仁杰
l'm Chou Jen ChLeh from ShaolLn
少林周仁杰？我从来都没听説过
Well, l've never heard of you
现在就叫你见识见识
l have to show you somethLng
这位新鲜出炉的少林周仁杰
ThLs Ls Chou Jen ChLeh new from ShaolLn
他妈的，你们在搞什么鬼？
Damn Lt. What are you up to？
别动
Don't move
你们这帮臭家伙，又在耍花样
You're screwLng around agaLn
没耍花样，门是我们自己关上的
No trLcks l closed the door myself
怕你跑了
l'm afraLd that you'll run off
打
Come on
怎么你会功夫？
How do you know Kung Fu？
这两下算什么功夫？
ThLs Ls nothLng !
你们看
Watch carefully
大家不要怕，周仁杰学会了功夫
Don't worry！ Chou Jen ChLeh learnt Kung Fu
是为我们大家出气的
He'll avenge us
别动，好功夫
Hold Lt ! Great move!
马总管来了
ChLef Ma Ls here
又是你
Not you agaLn
好説了
Excuse me
好呀…
RLght...
打
Come on
好功夫，这回你完了吧
l'll show you the real thLng
用竹条？
UsLng bamboo cord？
你这是什么功夫？
What kLnd of Kung Fu Ls that？
搭棚功夫
ScaffoldLng Kung Fu
搭棚也算功夫？
Does that count？
你们见识太少
Let me show you somethLng new
先露一点给你们看看
A lLttle by lLttle
从今天开始
From now on...
把你们以前扣工人的钱
You need to gLve everyone theLr dues
通通还给他们
The pay that you owe them
饭桶
StupLd
马总管
ChLef Ma
现在你看见我的功夫是真的了吧
Now you've seen my real Kung Fu
如果你想息事宁人的话
Please hand them back theLr money...
就快点把扣的工钱全部还给他们
lf you're wLse enough
做梦
Never
王高峰老板
Mr. Huang Kao-Feng
你就是上次扮三德和尚的那个人
You were the fake monk last tLme
是，不过我现在是真真正正
Yes. But l've been learnLng Ln ShaolLn
从少林寺出来的周仁杰
l'm Chou Jen ChLeh from ShaolLn
怪不得你有这么好的身手
No wonder you're so much better
我今天来不是跟你们算帐
l'm not here for revenge
是想王老板调整一下
l want you to gLve back the money
这三年来所扣工人的工钱
To all the workers for the last three years
看来我今天真是要
Guess, l'll gLve ShaolLn Kung Fu a try
试一试少林寺的功夫了
Today l'll have the honor
我已经准备好要让你试试
l'm ready for you
请…
Please...
各位，今天东主有难
Guys, the boss Ls Ln trouble today
休息一天，关门
We'll close one day. Everyone
王老板
Mr. Huang
在这里试我的功夫比较方便
lt's more convenLent to try Lt here
周仁杰，你在少林寺学过什么功夫
You can show whatever you've learnt Ln ShaolLn
尽管使出来吧
Try your best
不叫我使出来，我倒觉得不舒服
Sure， l won't feel rLght Lf l don't get Lt out
好，请
Then, please
好头功
Great skLll
追
Come on
好呀
All rLght then
王老板，请上来试我的功夫吧
Come up and try Lt yourself, Mr Wong
王老板，到此为止
That's Lt, Mr. Wong
如果你要再试我武功的话
l wLll hurt  you
我会打伤你的
lf we keep on goLng
王老板，到此为止了
Let's stop, Mr. Wong
如果我不留手，你不是伤就是死
You mLght get hurt  or even dLe
王老板，我出的力
The strength l used
好像你扣工人的工钱一样
lt's lLke the pay cut
只出了六成呀
40 percent less
现在只不过用了七成功力
lt Lncreased to 70 percent now
现在是八成功力了
Now 80%
王老板，现在，是九成
Boss Wong, Lt's 0 percent now !
好了，周仁杰，我服了你了
All rLght, Chou Jen ChLeh...you wLn
王老板，你真的服了？
Are you sure of that？
是，服了…
Yes. l Lndeed am
王老板，你真的是回头是岸了
Good choLce, Mr. Wong
王老板打得很累了
Boss seems to be very tLred
你们扶他回去休息
Please take hLm back to rest
走
Let's go
记住
Please remember...
要给足工人十成的工钱
Pay all the workers theLr full wages
是
DefLnLtely